Olivier Balaguer

London based UI/UX facilitator and developer with a focus on rapid prototyping. I help companies big and small create timeless digital touchpoints. The result: delightful experiences that leave a lasting impression. Want to change direction, change behaviour, or change the world? I can help out.

RECENT EXPERIENCE

Dream Yacht Group

Feb 2019 – Mar 2020 • UI Designer (Contract)

Redesigned main charter, sales and post-booking sites. Revamped Information Architecture and improved user flow across booking pages. Prototyped various concepts to key stakeholders. Unified Dream Yacht's brand identity across all sites. Designed a new suite of marketing email templates.

Vibe Pay

Jul – Dec 2018 • UI Designer (Contract)

Collaborated closely with developers. Designed various MVP concept prototypes. Created critical on-boarding user flow for the company's FCA Open Banking license application. Created responsive components in Angular for the desktop app.

Burberry

Jun 2017 - Jun 2018 • Email Developer (Contract)

Assisted Burberry's migration from Salesforce to SAP. Developed new suite of personalised email templates for Burberry's new brand refresh. Built interactive and sprite based movie email templates for use in bespoke campaigns. Implemented a data driven and modular workflow to localise Burberry's 13 international markets.

Ticketmaster UK

Nov 2016 - Apr 2017 • UI Designer (Contract)

Collaborated closely with developers, project and product managers within the Business Solutions team. Created various UI deliverables and concept prototypes for bespoke in-house SPAs.

Deliveroo

Jul - Sep 2016 • Email Developer (Contract)

Spearheaded the email development for Deliveroo's new rebrand. Integrated with various department heads to produce a suite of localised email templates (Transactional, CRM, Corporate and rider onboarding). Implemented a data driven and modular workflow to localise Deliveroo's 12 international markets.

M&C Saatchi

Jul 2015 - Jun 2016 • Email Developer (Contract)

Collaborated closely with designers, account managers, QA testers and project managers to translate highend designs intro fully responsive email campaigns/projects across O2, Land Rover, Virgin Holidays, IKEA Family, Compare The Market and East Midland Trains.

Future Cities Catapult

Sep - Nov 2015 • UI Designer (Contract)

Boarded during the second phase of development of OrganiCity. Tasked with steering the continuity of the designs to produce final deliverables and various SVG based assets. Liaised with project leaders and front-end developers in Denmark to ensure the cohesion of UI designs.

eBay Enterprise

Mar – Jul 2015 • Email Developer (Contract)

Operated in a large and fast paced agile team producing dynamic publishing solutions for *British Gas, British Airways, IKEA, Gumtree, Tesco Bank* and *Shop Direct Group*. Collaborated closely with account managers and clients to ensure timely deployment of campaigns.

PAST EXPERIENCE

Ticketmaster UK

Oct. 2011 - Jan. 2015 • Web Designer (Permanent)

As a primary role, I was the first port of call for Ticketmaster UK's marketing department. Conceptualised visual communications for both online and offline deliverables including, but not limited to:

- Micro sites and landing pages
- Responsive emails for B2C & B2B campaigns
- Online/Print ad campaigns
- White labelling for high profile brands/clients

Worked closely with a variety of stakeholders across the Ticketmaster family (LiveNation, TicketWeb, Get Me In!, Ticketmaster Systems) on an array of goods including, but not limited to:

- Interactive Seating Maps for venues across the UK
- Presentation decks for client pitches
- Bespoke TicketFast (e-tickets) templates
- Web applications

Accomplishments

- Mentored teammates on good practices
- Established time saving workflows
- Landing page designs used across
 Ticketmasters various markets worldwide
- Designed and developed all Ticketmasters marketing clients responsive email templates

Notable Projects

- Rugby World Cup 2015 email templates
- Glasgow 2014 email templates
- IRFU web allocation app redesign
- Millennium Stadium adverts

EDUCATION

Istituto Marangoni

2006 – 2009 • London, UK Graphic Design

Texas A&M University

2000 – 2003 • Corpus Christi, USA Business Administration

CORE SKILLS

Design Skills

Pencil and paper • Graphic/Art
Direction • Conceptualising •
Wireframing • Digital Art-working •
Adobe CC • Sketch • Figma

Tech Skills

Semantic HTML • Modern CSS • Javascript/ES6+ • Git • AMPscript (Salesforce)

Soft Skills

Mentoring • Collaborating • Workshopping • Adaptable • Effective communicator • Time/project management • Multilingual

INTERESTS

Still and time-lapse photography • Tinkering with my Raspberry Pi and Arduino • Stop Motion Animation • Motion Graphics • Typography • Screen Printing • Interactive Art Installations • Info Graphics and Data Visualisation • Sound Design • Processing • P5.js • Generative Art • Axidraw • Generative Adversarial Networks • Computer Vision • Augmented Reality • Virtual Reality